Principal Software Engineer $\,\cdot\,$ Product Architecture $\,\cdot\,$ Technical Strategy

Raleigh, NC, USA | US Citizen

Summary_

Bring my proven technical leadership in the cybersecurity and operations industry to bear on interesting projects. Help with small and large architectural projects, solve complicated issues that customers experience, and organize teams towards both short and long-term objectives.

Experience ____

Tanium Morrisville, NC - Hybrid

PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER - PRODUCT TECHNICAL STRATEGY

- Founded and lead the Product Technical Strategy Team at Tanium after identifying a gap in communication between Product Management and Engineering
- Identify technical patterns across R&D, and formalize solutions and guidelines for all of engineering.
- Engage in complex customer escalations
- Serve as architect for projects that span the entire Engineering organization

STAFF SOFTWARE ENGINEER - PLATFORM

Mar. 2021 - Dec. 2022

Dec. 2022 - Present

- · Working on native extensions to the Tanium Client for products such as Tanium Recorder, Stream, and Threat Response
- Lead development of strategic initiatives across the R&D organization
- · Lead an effort to reduce the footprint of the Tanium Client across our customer base, focusing on CPU, memory, and IO reductions

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - THREAT RESPONSE

lun. 2019 - Mar. 202

- Helped launch a new endpoint extension to the Tanium Client: Tanium Stream. Stream allows customers to use Tanium to send endpoint telemetry directly to any datalake
- · Helped with the launch of Threat Response 2.0, a major change to the Threat Response product
- Created a monorepo for endpoint extensions and facilitated adoption across the Endpoint team

BM Raleigh, NC - Hybrid

DEVELOPER TEAM LEAD / SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - QRADAR ADVISOR WITH WATSON

Jul. 2018 - Jun. 2019

- Served as senior team architect for on-premises and cloud products for Cybersecurity
- Advised development team of 15 developers and oversaw day-to-day work. Aligned team's work with Product Management and Engineering Management objectives

DEVELOPER TEAM LEAD / ADVISORY SOFTWARE ENGINEER - QRADAR ADVISOR WITH WATSON

Jul. 2017 - Jul. 2018

- Lead team building cybersecurity applications on top of the QRader SIEM
- · Promoted to advise development team of 15 developers and oversaw day-to-day work

Atlanta, GA - Onsite

STAFF SOFTWARE ENGINEER - QRADAR ADVISOR WITH WATSON

· Created the QRadar Application dockerized build framework and oversaw implementation for other apps

Apr. 2016 - Jun. 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - X-FORCE THREAT INTELLIGENCE & IDS/IPS DEVELOPMENT

· Improved production system uptime to 99.9% as the sole North American Systems Operations Engineer

May. 2014 - Apr. 2016

SECURITY SOFTWARE INTERN - X-FORCE THREAT INTELLIGENCE

• Worked on targeted research and software solutions within the IBM X-Force QA Team

May 2013 - May 2014

• Rewrote the front-end and back-end of a global security research sensor network in latest language stacks

University of Virginia Charlottesville, VA, USA

RESIDENT ADVISOR

Aug. 2012 - May 2014

• Planned programs and facilitated academic integrity for 36 residents over two academic years

Implus Footcare, LLC

IT DEVELOPMENT ASSOCIATE Aug. 2011 - Aug. 2011

• Developed targeted modular projects for centralized data organization for company intranet

IT DEPARTMENT INTERN
Summer 2009, 2010, 2011

• Modernized company intranet code, integrated Active Directory

Education

University of Virginia - B.S. in Computer Science

CONCENTRATION: COMPUTER SECURITY | MAJOR GPA 3.0

Charlottesville, VA, USA Graduated May 2014